Guide to the Franco Modigliani papers, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1970s-2003 RL.00905
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1944-2003 and undated, bulk 1960-2000, 26 boxes
  - Confederazione Italiana Sindacati Lavoratori, 1993 (Box CO5)
  - Consiglio Italiano per le Scienze Sociali, 1976-1983 (Box CO5)
  - Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche (Italian version of the National Science Foundation), 1991 (Box CO5)
  - Contini, Bruno, 1977-1986 (Box CO5)
  - Corriere della Sera, 1974 (Box CO5)
  - Costa Plan, 1976 (Box CO5)
  - Costa Rica (See Econometric Society), 1988 (Box CO5)
  - Cox, Donald, 1987 (Box CO5)
  - Cozzi, Terenzio, 1987 (Box CO5)
  - D General, 1977-1992 (Box CO5)
  - Daum, Audrey, 1987-1990 (Box CO6)
  - Davidson, Paul, 1963 (Box CO6)
  - De Boissieu, Christian, 1979-1980 and 1987 (Box CO6)
  - Debreu, Gerard, 1949 (Box CO6)
  - de Menil, George, 1975 and 1981 (Box CO6)
  - de Quinto, Javier, 1994-1995 (Box CO6)
  - Diamond, Peter, 1993-1999 (Box CO6)
  - Domar, Evsey D., 1949 (Box CO6)
  - Drèze, Jacques
    - 1954-1972 (Box CO6)
    - 1974-2003 and undated (Box CO6)
  - E General, 1977-2003 (Box CO6)
  - Eastern Economic Association, 1988 (Box CO6)
  - Eberstadt, Walter, 1986 (Box CO6)
  - Econometric Society, 1974-1989 (Box CO6)
  - Economia Italiana, 1992 (Box CO6)
  - Economic Notes Advisory Board, 1990 (Box CO6)
  - Economic Policy Institute, 1989 (Box CO6)
  - Edwards, Jack, undated (Box CO6)
  - Eguchi Conference, 1982-1984 (Box CO6)
  - Economists Against the Arms Race, 1988-1997 (Box CO6)
  - Einaudi Editore: Italian Collection, 1979-1991 and undated (Box CO7)
  - Eisner, Robert, 1977-1995 and undated, 2 folders (Box CO7)
  - Elsevier Science, 1995 (Box CO7)
  - Eliasson, Gunnar, 1975-1986 (Box CO7)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1993 (Box CO7)
  - EPTA Fund, 1986 (Box CO7)
  - European Economic Association, 1988-1989 (Box CO7)
  - F General, 1978-1991, 2002, 2 folders (Box CO7)
  - Fabozzi, Frank, 1985 (Box CO7)
  - Fanjul, Oscar, 1995-1997 (Box CO7)
  - Fazio, Antonio, 1961-1962, 1993 (Box CO7)
  - Feiwel, George, 1977-1987 (Box CO7)
  - Financial Times, 1990 (Box CO7)
  - Fitoussi, Jean-Paul, 1978-1984 (Box CO7)
  - Forsyth, Douglas, 1987-1991 (Box CO8)
  - Foxley, Alejandro (and CIEPLAN [Centro de Estudios de Planificacion Nacional]), 1980-1984 (Box CO8)
  - Francesco, Franco, 2000, 2002-2003 (Box CO8)
  - Franco Modigliani Chair in Financial Economics, 1993-1995 (Box CO8)
  - Franz, Juergen, 1989 (Box CO8)
  - French Revolution Bicentennial, 1988 (Box CO8)
  - Friedman, Benjamin, 1988-1990 (Box CO8)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1987 (Box CO8)
  - Fulbright Scholar Trip to Europe, 1953-1955 and undated (Box CO8)
  - G General, 1970-2000, 2 folders (Box CO8)
  - Gallegati, Mauro, 1988 (Box CO8)
  - Gasparini, Innocenzo, 1947 (Box CO8)
  - Gates, Jeff, 1989-1995 (Box CO8)
  - General Correspondence
    - 1942-1964, 5 folders (Box CO8)
    - 1971-2003 and undated, 1-15 of 16 folders (Box CO9)
    - 1971-2003 and undated, 16 of 16 folders (Box CO10)
  - German Marshall Fund, 1977-1979 (Box CO10)
  - Giavazzi, Francesco, 1974-1986 (Box CO10)
  - Gillies, Grazia, 1980-1981 (Box CO10)
  - Giovannini, Albert, 1988 (Box CO10)
  - Gorga, Carmine, 1977-1998, 2 folders (Box CO10)
  - Grunberg, Emile, 1954-1962, 1979 (Box CO10)
  - Gruppo Esponenti Italiani, undated (Box CO10)
  - Guido Dorso Prize, 1989 (Box CO10)
  - H General, 1984-1994 (Box CO10)
  - H General, 1971-1983, 2003 (Box CO11)
  - Hall, Bob, circa 1990s (Box CO11)
  - Hart, Albert, 1952 (Box CO11)
  - Hart, Albert - Monetary policy, 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box CO11)
  - Harnett, William J., 1992-2001 (Box CO11)
  - Harvard Appointment, 1957 (Box CO11)
  - Harvard Job Offer, 1946 (Box CO11)
  - Heflebower, Richard, 1959-1960 (Box CO11)
  - Henin, P.Y., 1978-1980 and undated (Box CO11)
  - Hickman, Bert, 1989 (Box CO11)
  - Horioka, Charles, 1991-1993 (Box CO11)
  - Horn and Company, 1989-1990 (Box CO11)
  - Hsu, Michelle, 1993 (Box CO11)
  - Hungarian correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box CO11)
  - Hurd, Michael, 1986-1987 (Box CO11)
  - I General, 1979-1995 (Box CO11)
  - Indian correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box CO11)
  - Indian Institute of Finances, 1987-1995 (Box CO11)
  - Indian Journal of Applied Economics, 1995-1999 (Box CO11)
  - Ingrao, Bruna, 1980-1982 (Box CO11)
  - Institut National de la Statistique et des tudes Economiques - Fifi model, undated (Box CO12)
  - Institute for International Economics, 1987 (Box CO12)
  - Institute for Social Research, 1987-1988 (Box CO12)
  - International Association of Financial Engineers, 1995-1998 (Box CO12)
  - International Center for Advanced Economic Research, circa 1987 (Box CO12)
  - International Monetary Fund, 1973-1976, 1991, 1994 (Box CO12)
  - International Network for Economic Method, 1989-1990 (Box CO12)
  - Interviews, 2003 (Box CO12)
  - Invernizzi, Emanuele, 1988-1989 (Box CO12)
  - Invitations, 1951-1959 (Box CO12)
  - Istituto Italiano Di Credito Fondiano, 1976-1978 and undated (Box CO12)
  - Istituto per l'Assistenza allo Sviluppo del Mezzogiorno, 1994 (Box CO12)
  - Italian correspondence, 1986-2003 (Box CO12)
  - Italian scholarships, 1989 (Box CO12)
  - Italian Minister of Finance, Rome (per T. Padoa-Schioppa): Mazzillo, 1991 (Box CO12)
  - J General, 1977-1994, 1998 (Box CO12)
  - Japanese correspondence, 1989 (Box CO12)
  - Jappelli, Tullio, 1984-1996, 2000-2003 and undated, 2 folders (Box CO12)
  - Jaszi, George, 1978-1979 (Box CO12)
  - Jimenez, Josephine, 1980, 1988-1989 (Box CO12)
  - Jin, Zhongxia, 1991-1992 (Box CO12)
  - Jorgensen, Dale and Barbara Fraumeni, 1994-1995 (Box CO12)
  - Jesse Jackson 1988 Campaign, 1988 (Box CO12)
  - Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 1974-1982 (Box CO12)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, 1984-1986 (Box CO12)
  - Jozzo, Alfonso, 1979-1983 (Box CO12)
  - K General, 1977-1984 (Box CO12)
  - K General, 1985-1995 (Box CO13)
  - Kemp-Roth Bill, 1978 (Box CO13)
  - Killian Award, 1985 (Box CO13)
  - Kisselgoff, Avram, 1956-1958 (Box CO13)
  - Klein, Lawrence, 2003 (Box CO13)
  - Koopmans, Tjalling, 1947-1948 (Box CO13)
  - Kotlikoff, Laurence, 1995 (Box CO13)
  - Kouri, Pentti (obsolete), 1985 (Box CO13)
  - Kuznets, Simon, 1946 (Box CO13)
  - Kuh, Edwin, 1963 (Box CO13)
  - L General, 1976-1996, 2000-2001 (Box CO13)
  - La Malfa, Giorgio, 1967-1990 (Box CO13)
  - Layard, Richard, 1985-1989 (Box CO13)
  - The Leigh Bureau, 1985-1986 (Box CO13)
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1995 (Box CO13)
  - Leontief, Wassily, 1944, 1947 (Box CO13)
  - Lerner, Abba, 1943, 1947 (Box CO13)
  - Letters
    - General, 1997-1998, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box CO13)
    - General, 1999, 3 of 3 folders (Box CO14)
  - Letters about Modigliani's work, 2002-2003 (Box CO14)
  - Leukemia research, 1990 (Box CO14)
  - Levi-Montalcini, Rita, 1991-1992 (Box CO14)
  - Levy Economics Institute, 1989-1993 (Box CO14)
  - "Liquidity Preference and the Theory of Interest and Money," 1943-1947 (Box CO14)
  - Lombardi, Alessandro, 1988-1991 (Box CO14)
  - Lubell, Harold, 1944-1947, 2003 (Box CO14)
  - Lundberg, Gertrud, 1989-1991 (Box CO14)
  - Lybeck, Johan, 1973-1981 (Box CO14)
  - Lybeck, Johann, 1974, 2 folders (Box CO15)
  - M General, 1974-2002, 3 folders (Box CO15)
  - Marschak, Jacob, 1941-1948, 1976 (Box CO15)
  - Mason, Andrew, 1982-1983 (Box CO15)
  - Massachusetts Congressional Delegation, 1985 (Box CO15)
  - Massimiliano Kolbe, Associazione Culturelle, 1985-1987 (Box CO15)
  - Mayer, Thomas, 1976 (Box CO15)
  - Meat shortage proposal, 1947-1948, 2 folders (Box CO15 A)
  - Mediocredito Centrale, 1986-1991 (Box CO15 A)
  - Menges, Dr., 1961 (Box CO15 A)
  - Merton, 1969 term paper, [Robert Merton?] 1995 (Box CO15 A)
  - Mexican correspondence, 1986, 1993 (Box CO15 A)
  - Miller, Merton, 1960-1965, 1995, 2000, 2 folders (Box CO15 A)
  - MIT-FRB [Massachusetts Institute of Technology-Federal Reserve Bank] Model
    - General, 1969 (Box CO15 A)
    - Gramlich, Ned, 1969-1970 (Box CO15 A)
    - Social Science Research Council Subcommittee, 1969-1970 (Box CO15 A)
  - MIT Industrial Liaison Program, 1985-1988 (Box CO16)
  - Modigliana [town], 1993 and 1999 (Box CO16)
  - Modigliani, Andr, 1963 (Box CO16)
  - Modigliani, Leah, 1997-2003 (Box CO16)
  - Monti, Mario, 1989 (Box CO16)
  - Morgan, Guaranty, 1991 (Box CO16)
  - Moynihan, Patrick, 1992 (Box CO16)
  - Muralidhar, Arun, 2003 (Box CO16)
  - Musumeci, Giuseppe, 1983-1984 (Box CO16)
  - N General, 1977-1990 (Box CO16)
  - Nasrallah, May, 1991-1992 (Box CO16)
  - National Academy of Science, 1973-1991 (Box CO16)
  - National Science Foundation, 1971-1990 (Box CO16)
  - Netherlands correspondence, 1993 (Box CO16)
  - New America High Income Fund, 1991 (Box CO16)
  - New Jersey College for Women, 1942 (Box CO16)
  - New School for Social Science Research, 1942-1947 (Box CO16)
  - New School for Social Science Research: Visiting Committee to the Graduate Faculty, 1985-1997 (Box CO16)
  - The New York Times, 1948 (Box CO16)
  - Nihon Keizai Shimbun, 1988-1990 (Box CO16)
  - Nobel Foundation, 1999-2001 (Box CO16)
  - Nobel Prize
    - A General, 1985-1986 (Box CO16)
    - Autograph requests, 1985-1987 (Box CO16)
    - B General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - C General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - D General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - E, F General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - G General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - Greeting cards, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - H General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - I General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - J-K General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - L General, 1985-1986 (Box CO17)
    - Larry Speakes, 1985 (Box CO17)
    - Letters of congratulations, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
      - A-G (Box CO18)
      - Fraulein Pabst (Box CO18)
      - H-Z, 2 folders (Box CO18)
    - M General, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
    - Media requests, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
    - N-P General, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box CO18)
    - Paper requests, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
    - Phone calls
      - Europe, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
      - Friends, [1985?] (Box CO18)
      - Luncheons/Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box CO18)
    - Prize letter, 1985 (Box CO18)
    - R-S General, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box CO18)
    - Stockholm, 1985-1986 (Box CO19)
    - T-Z General, 1985-1986, 3 folders (Box CO19)
  - Noera, Mario, 1979 (Box CO19)
  - O General, 1974-1992, 2000 (Box CO19)
  - O'Donnell, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box CO19)
  - Owers, Jim, 1996 (Box CO19)
  - Oxford University Press, 1994 (Box CO19)
  - P General, 1977-2002, 2 folders (Box CO19)
  - Pacific Basin Capital Markets, 1991 (Box CO19)
  - Padoa-Schioppa, Fiorella, 1994-1998 and undated (Box CO19)
  - Padoa-Schioppa, Tommaso, 1976-1993 (Box CO19)
  - Pagano, Marco, 1988-1993, 2 folders (Box CO19)
  - Panorama: Pino Buongiornio, 1989 (Box CO19)
  - Papademos, Lucas, 1975-1976 (Box CO19)
  - Pasinetti Paradox correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box CO20)
  - Pasinetti, Luigi, 1958-1961, 1995 and 2003 (Box CO20)
  - Patinkin, Don, 1947-1948 (Box CO20)
  - Pavesi, Alberto (Instituto di Credito Fondiario delle Venezie), 1988 (Box CO20)
  - Il Pensiero Economico Moderno, 1987-1988 (Box CO20)
  - Permissions for republication, 1977-1995 (Box CO20)
  - Petitions and protest letters
    - 1987-2003 and undated, 2 folders (Box CO20)
    - Silvio Berlusconi, 2003 (Box CO20)
  - Perotti, Enrico, 1986-1994, 3 folders (Box CO20)
  - Picker, Hans, 1982 (Box CO20)
  - Pierides, Ioannis, 1987 (Box CO20)
  - Pitagora, 1983-1988 (Box CO20)
  - Pogue, Gerry
    - 1973-1976 (Box CO20)
    - Margrabe problem, 1975-1976 (Box CO20)
  - Porterba, James - Conference on research in income and wealth, 1988 (Box CO20)
  - Promostudio - Giovanni Vescovo, 1989-1993 (Box CO20)
  - Q General, 1979 (Box CO20)
  - R General, 1977-1999, 2 folders (Box CO21)
  - RAI Corporation [Italian Radio TV System], 1977-1993 (Box CO21)
  - Rasche, Robert, 1967-1972 (Box CO21)
  - Recommendation letters
    - A-F, 1968-2002, 8 folders (Box CO21)
    - F-R, 1968-2002, 13 folders (Box CO22)
    - S-Z, 1968-2002, 3 folders (Box CO23)
  - Ren, Huaixiu, 1991 (Box CO23)
  - Revue franaise d'conomie, 1986 (Box CO23)
  - Rie, Daniel, 1971-1972 (Box CO23)
  - ROCHE [Hoffman-La Roche, Inc.] agreement, 1974 (Box CO23)
  - Romero-Maura, Joaquin, 1978-1980 (Box CO23)
  - Rousselot, John H., 1977 (Box CO23)
  - Russian correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box CO23)
  - S General, 1976-2003, 3 folders (Box CO23)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1949 (Box CO23)
  - Samuelson, Paul, 1943 and 1960-1998 (Box CO23)
  - Sato, Ryuzo, 1987 (Box CO24)
  - Scholarships [for Italians], 1989 (Box CO24)
  - Schultze, Charles, 1977 and 1989 (Box CO24)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1946 (Box CO24)
  - Siedman Distinguished Award in Political Economy, 1975-1977 and 1991 (Box CO24)
  - Shackle, G.L.S., 1959 (Box CO24)
  - Shapiro, Eli, 1998 (Box CO24)
  - Shiller, Robert, 1977-1981 and 1993 (Box CO24)
  - Showalter, Mark, circa 1989-1990 (Box CO24)
  - Shiskin, Julius, 1976-1977 (Box CO24)
  - Siena [Instituto di credito di diritto pubblico], 1990 (Box CO24)
  - Simha, Evelyn, 1985 and 1991 (Box CO24)
  - Simon, Herbert, 1951-1960 and 1993-2003 (Box CO24)
  - Sinclair, Peter, 1990 (Box CO24)
  - Sloan Business and Public Policy Group, 1988 (Box CO24)
  - Sloan School of Management, MIT, 1994-1995 (Box CO24)
  - Slovenia consulting [ljublijanska banka], 1991-1993 (Box CO24)
  - Societ Italiana Degli Economisti, 1976-1992 (Box CO24)
  - Solow, Robert, 1946 (Box CO24)
  - Sonnino, Edward, 1981-1982 (Box CO24)
  - Soros, George, 1987 (Box CO24)
  - Spanish correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box CO24)
  - Spilimbergo, Antonio, 1993-1994 (Box CO24)
  - Spingardi, Tomaso, 1988 (Box CO24)
  - Stigler, George, 1959 (Box CO24)
  - St. John's University, 1991 (Box CO24)
  - Sterling, Arlie, 1978-1987 (Box CO24)
  - Stimulus coalition, 2002-2003 (Box CO24)
  - Summer Institute for International Cooperation (Jan Tinbergen), 1992 (Box CO24)
  - Sylos Labini, Paolo, 1956-1987 and 1995 (Box CO24)
  - Szeg, Giorgio, 1978-1984 (Box CO24)
  - T General, 1977-2003 (Box CO24)
  - Tantazzi, Angelo, 1975-1979 (Box CO25)
  - Taylor, John, 1987 (Box CO25)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association-College Retirement Equities Fund [TIAA-CREF], 1979 and 1988 (Box CO25)
  - Tel-Aviv International School of Management [TISOM], International Academic Committee, 1994-1995 (Box CO25)
  - Tellez, Luis, 1993 (Box CO25)
  - Thieme, Christopher, 1990 (Box CO25)
  - Tintner, Gerhard, 1944 (Box CO25)
  - Treasury Department, 1967-1969 (Box CO25)
  - Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service - Intergenerational Wealth Study, 1989 (Box CO25)
  - Trezza, Bruno, 1967 (Box CO25)
  - Turkish correspondence, 1986 and 1993 (Box CO25)
  - Tyler Prize [for Environmental Achievement], 1986 (Box CO25)
  - U General, 1974-1989 (Box CO25)
  - United States Information Agency, 1975-1976 (Box CO25)
  - Universidade Nova de Lisboa, 1990 (Box CO25)
  - University of Islamabad, 1976-1977 (Box CO25)
  - University of Zagreb, Yugoslavia, 1990-1991 (Box CO25)
  - US Air, 1995 (Box CO25)
  - US-USSR Conference on Economic Modeling, 1975 (Box CO25)
  - V General, 1977-1989, 2003 (Box CO25)
  - Velsquez, Jose, 1996 (Box CO25)
  - Vigorelli, Giuseppe, 1978-1980 (Box CO25)
  - Visentini, Bruno, 1974, 1976, 1984 (Box CO25)
  - Vitagliano, Francis, 1986-1993 (Box CO25)
  - Vito Volterra Collection, 1982-1984 (Box CO25)
  - W General, 1975-1981 (Box CO25)
  - W General, 1981-1994, 1999, 2003 (Box CO26)
  - War correspondence (with students serving), 1944 (Box CO26)
  - Weintraub, Sidney, 1974 (Box CO26)
  - Who's Who Updates, 1995 (Box CO26)
  - Worms, Andreas, 1995 (Box CO26)
  - Wurzburger, Ben, 1975-1976 (Box CO26)
  - X-Z General, 1975-1991 (Box CO26)
  - Yamashita, Hiroaki, 1989 (Box CO26)
  - Yashiro, Hiroko, 1992 (Box CO26)
  - Young, Warren, 1991 (Box CO26)
  - Zhu, Jia-Ming (Prospectus for the Asia-Pacific Financial Center), 1995 (Box CO26)
  - Zironi, Alberto, 1995 (Box CO26)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1936-2004 and undated, 58 boxes
  Largest series in the collection. Arranged into the following subseries: Research and Writings, Speeches and Lectures, Writings by Others, and Non-Academic Works. See subseries descriptions below.
  - Research and Writings Subseries, 1936-2004 and undated, bulk 1960-2003, 44 boxes
    Contains extensive documentation related to Modigliani's research and to the writing of his articles, papers, or book-length works. It includes several early writings by Modigliani, most notably his doctoral thesis, circa 1944, "The General Theory of Employment Interest and Money Under the Assumptions of Flexible Prices and of Fixed Prices" (New School of Social Research). Other writings from 1936-2003 can be found in the Non-Academic Works Subseries below, and in the Printed Materials Series, which houses reprints of almost all published articles by Modigliani. Research notes and correspondence are often organized in folders with the titles of the published work to which the materials relate. Other folders of research notes are categorized by subject terms. Formats include correspondence, drafts of writings, data, research notes, bibliographies, and econometric estimations. Major topics include econometric modeling; the life-cycle hypothesis of savings; social security; European Union and Italian economies; government economic policies; inflation; unemployment (especially in Europe); and mortgages. Other groups of materials represent Modigliani's long-term involvement with various projects, including the "MPS" model (an abbreviation deriving from the collaborators -- MIT, Penn State, and the Social Sciences Research Council) of the U.S. economy, sponsored by the United States Federal Reserve, and the NSF-funded project in the 1980s on monetary mechanisms and stabilization policies. There are also materials that pertain to Modigliani's memoirs, Adventures of an Economist, published in 2003.
    This subseries also includes Modigliani's comments on papers written by others. In this case, the comments are in a folder with the title of the original paper followed by "comments, F. Modigliani" and date. Overall, the subseries is further enhanced by the frequent presence of related correspondence between Modigliani and his co-authors or commentators, as well as printed materials (such as reports, clippings, reprints and journal articles) and writings by others, both published and unpublished, related to Modigliani's research. Significant collaborators and correspondents include S. L. Cao, Tullio Jappelli, Tommaso Padoa-Schioppa, Robert Solow, and Arlie Sterling. Arranged in alphabetical order by title of work, by subject, or by personal last name, then chronologically within folders.
    - Addendum: Is a Tax Rebate an Effective Tool for Stabilization Policy? with C. Steindel, 1977-1980 (Box RW1)
    - Administrative Proposal for Restructuring the Savings and Loan Industry, undated (Box RW1)
    - Adventures of an Economist, circa 2001, 4 folders (Box RW1)
    - The Age-Saving Profile and the Life-Cycle Hypothesis, with T. Jappelli, 1999 (Box RW1)
    - Aggregate Unemployment in Italy: 1960-1983, with F. Padoa-Schioppa and N. Rossi, 1986 (Sussex Conference) (Box RW1)
    - Alternative Investment Performance Fee Arrangements and Implications for Regulatory Policy, with G. Pogue, 1975 (Box RW1)
    - Ando, A. - Monetary theory notes, circa 1960, Folder 1 of 2 (Box RW1)
    - Ando, A. - Monetary theory notes, circa 1960, Folder 2 of 2 (Box RW2)
    - Aspects of the Costs of Inflation, with S. Fisher, 1977-1979 (Box RW2)
    - Aspects of the World Economy in War and Peace, A. J. Brown - Notes, undated (Box RW2)
    - The Balance of Payment and International Liquidity Problem and Its Implications for Domestic and International Trade Policies, 1968 Mar. 27 (Box RW2)
    - Balance of Payments: Implications of the Oil Crisis and How to Handle Them Through International Cooperation, 1974 Jan. 24 (Box RW2)
    - Balance Sheets for the U.S. Economy: 1945-1980, 1981 Oct. (Box RW2)
    - Baldassarri, Mario, 1993-1996 and undated (Box RW2)
    - Bank for International Settlements: NSF (National Science Foundation) conference proposal, 1981 (Box RW2)
    - Bernstein, Peter, 1989 and undated (Box RW2)
    - A Better Solution to the Social Security Crisis - MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) Team
      - Correspondence, 2000 (Box RW2)
      - An MIT Solution to the Social Security Crisis, with Ceprini and Muralidhar
        - Original and first revision, 1999 (Box RW2)
        - Second revision, 1999 July (Box RW2)
        - Third revision, 1999 Nov. (Box RW2)
        - Fourth revision, 2001 Jan. (Box RW2)
        - Referee Reports, 2001 (Box RW2)
      - Printed material, 2000 Feb. (Box RW2)
    - Beveridge curves, 1994-1995 (Box RW2)
    - Black Monday in Retrospect and Prospect, with M. Feldstein, A. Sinai, and R. Solow, 1988 (Box RW3)
    - Bond Market, in the New Palgrave Dictionary of Money and Finance, with F. Fabozzi, 1992 (Box RW3)
    - Bossons, John - Various papers written with F. Modigliani, 1963-1965 and undated, 6 folders (Box RW3)
    - The Bugaboo of Double Taxation, with R. Solow, 2003 (Box RW3)
    - Business cycles, 1998-1999 (Box RW3)
    - Business Expectations and Strategy for the United States of Europe, with H. Askari, 1997 (Box RW3)
    - Capital Markets, Institutions, and Instruments, with F. Fabozzi, 1992, 1994 (Box RW3)
    - Capital Movements: A Note for K. Froot and A. Mello, 1989 Nov. 11 (Box RW3)
    - Case for Mixed Funded-Pay-as-you-go Schemes, with Arun Muralidhar, undated (Box RW3)
    - Il Caso Italia, Mondadori, 1985-1987 and undated (Box RW3)
    - Central Bank Policy, the Money Supply, and the Short-term Rate of Interest, with R. Rasche and J. P. Cooper, 1970, 2 folders (Box RW3)
    - Changes in the Balance Sheet of the U.S. Manufacturing Sector, 1926-1977, J. H. Ciccolo and C. H. Baum - Comments by F. Modigliani, 1983 (Box RW3)
    - Channels of Monetary Policy in the FMP Econometric Model of the U.S., 1975 (Box RW3)
    - China - Notes on inflation, national accounting and growth, 1993 (Box RW3)
    - The Chinese Saving Puzzle and the Life-Cycle Hypothesis
      - Correspondence with S. L. Cao, 1994-1997 (Box RW3)
      - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box RW4)
      - Data and tests, 1993-2001, 3 folders (Box RW4)
      - Draft and published paper with S. L. Cao, 2004 (Box RW4)
      - Drafts and revisions with S. L. Cao, 1993-1996, 4 folders (Box RW4)
      - Modigliani- Brumber paper, 2003 (Box RW4)
      - Notes, 1997-2003, 2 folders (Box RW4)
      - Notes and data, undated (Box RW4)
      - Old outdated I, 1996-1997 (Box RW4)
      - Old outdated II, 1996-1997 (Box RW4)
    - The Collected Papers of Franco Modigliani
      - Book permissions and contract, 1978-1987 (Box RW4)
      - Chinese translation, 1985-1994 (Box RW4)
      - Co-authors, 1978-1979 (Box RW5)
      - Hungarian translation, 1986-1990 (Box RW5)
      - Italian translation, 1978-1991 (Box RW5)
      - Korean translation, 1986 (Box RW5)
      - Reviews, 1980-1981 (Box RW5)
      - Suggested contents and miscellaneous, 1987 (Box RW5)
    - Comments and essays, Modigliani, 1962-1984 and undated (Box RW5)
    - Comments on Rollover Mortgages, 1980 Jan. (Box RW5)
    - Concord coalition - Notes and correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box RW5)
    - Consumption and Consumer Expenditure, with A. Ando - Appendix A, 1970 (Box RW5)
    - Consumption and Corporate Saving, W. Weber - Comments, F. Modigliani, circa 1970 (Box RW5)
    - Consumption Decisions Under Uncertainty, with J. Drze, 1963 Feb. (Box RW5)
    - The Consumption Function in a Developing Economy and the Italian Experience, with E. Tarantelli
      - Drafts, 1975 (Box RW5)
      - Notes, 1975 (Box RW5)
    - Consumption and reduced form estimation
      - Consumption, Boston Federal, 1972 and undated (Box RW5)
      - Graphs, undated (Box RW5)
      - Reduced forms - printed material, 1968-1971 (Box RW5)